<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/config/</guid><description>Configuration Quartz is designed to be extremely configurable. You can find the bulk of the configuration scattered throughout the repository depending on how in-depth you&amp;rsquo;d like to get.
The majority of configuration can be be found under data/config.yaml. An annotated example configuration is shown below.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 name:Your name here!# Shows in the footerenableToc:true# Whether to show a Table of Contentsdescription:Page description to show to search enginespage_title:Quartz Example Page# Default Page Titlelinks:# Links to show in footer- link_name:Twitterlink:https://twitter.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Quartz to the Web</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/hosting/</guid><description>GitHub Pages Quartz is designed to be effortless to deploy. If you forked and cloned Quartz directly from the repository, everything should already be good to go! You can head to &amp;lt;YOUR-GITHUB-USERNAME.github.io/quartz to see it live.
Enable GitHub Actions By default, GitHub disables workflows from running automatically on Forked Repostories. Head to the &amp;lsquo;Actions&amp;rsquo; tab of your forked repository and Enable Workflows to setup deploying your Quartz site!
Enable GitHub Actions</description></item><item><title>Editing Content in Quartz</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/editing/</guid><description>Editing Quartz runs on top of Hugo so all notes are written in Markdown .
Obsidian I strongly recommend using Obsidian as a way to edit and grow your digital garden. It comes with a really nice editor and graphical interface to preview all of my local files.
🔗 How to link your Obsidian Vault
Of course, all the files are in Markdown so you could just use your favourite text editor of choice.</description></item><item><title>Ignoring Notes</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/ignore-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/ignore-notes/</guid><description>Quartz Ignore Edit ignoreFiles in config.toml to include paths you&amp;rsquo;d like to exclude from being rendered.
1 2 3 4 5 6 ... ignoreFiles = [ &amp;#34;/content/templates/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;/content/private/*&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;your path here&amp;gt;&amp;#34; ] ignoreFiles supports the use of Regular Expressions (RegEx) so you can ignore patterns as well (e.g. ignoring all .pngs by doing \\.png$). To ignore a specific file, you can also add the tag draft: true to the frontmatter of a note.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Vault Integration</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/obsidian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/obsidian/</guid><description>Setup Obsidian is the preferred way to use Quartz. You can either create a new Obsidian Vault or link one that your already have.
New Vault If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an existing Vault, download Obsidian and create a new Vault in the /content folder that you created and cloned during the setup .
Linking an existing Vault The easiest way to use an existing Vault is to copy all of our files (directory and hierarchies intact) into the /content folder.</description></item><item><title>Preview Changes</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/preview-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/preview-changes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview what your Quartz site looks like before deploying it to the internet, here&amp;rsquo;s exactly how to do that!
Install hugo-obsidian This step will generate the list of backlinks for Hugo to parse. Ensure you have Go (&amp;gt;= 1.16) installed.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 # Install and link `hugo-obsidian` locally $ go install github.com/jackyzha0/hugo-obsidian # Navigate to your local Quartz folder $ cd &amp;lt;location-of-your-local-quartz&amp;gt; # Scrape all links in your Quartz folder and generate info for Quartz $ hugo-obsidian -input=content -output=data -index=true Afterwards, start the Hugo server as shown above and your local backlinks and interactive graph should be populated!</description></item><item><title>Quartz Philosophy</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/philosophy/</guid><description>“[One] who works with the door open gets all kinds of interruptions, but [they] also occasionally gets clues as to what the world is and what might be important.” — Richard Hamming
Why Quartz? Hosting a public digital garden isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. There are an overwhelming number of tutorials, resources, and guides for tools like Notion , Roam , and Obsidian , yet none of them have super easy to use free tools to publish that garden to the world.</description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/setup/</guid><description>Making your own Quartz Setting up Quartz requires a basic understanding of git. If you are unfamiliar, this resource is a great place to start!
Forking A fork is a copy of a repository. Forking a repository allows you to freely experiment with changes without affecting the original project.
Navigate to the GitHub repository for the Quartz project:
📁 Quartz Repository Then, Fork the repository into your own GitHub account.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting and FAQ</title><link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/notes/troubleshooting/</guid><description>Common Pitfalls Can I publish only a subset of my pages? Yes! Quartz makes selective publishing really easy. Heres a guide on excluding pages from being published .
Can I host this myself and not on GitHub Pages? Yes! All built files can be found under /public in the master branch. More details under hosting .
Do I need a website already? No! Setting up Quartz means you set up a site too :)</description></item></channel></rss>